ORIGINAL STORY BY NATSU HYUUGA
（原作：日向夏）
THIS STORY IS A FICION, AND ALL NAMES OF FIGURES ND ORGANIZATIONS ARE FICTITIOUS.
（本作所有人物、組織名均為虛構）
MOREOVER, THE STORY HAS NO RELATION TO REAL-LIFE INCIDENTS AND EVENTS.
（與任何特定事件或現象無關）
-Are you serious? -Of course.
-您是認真的嗎？ -當然
Maomao came back, so now's our chance, right?
貓貓好不容易回來了嘛
All done. Unlike the rear palace,
就這樣吧，跟後宮不一樣
there are no good medicinal herbs in the outer palace.
外廷並沒有好的藥草
I have to keep growing more bit by bit.
不慢慢多種一點的話…
Xiaomao.
小貓
Didn't I ask you to clean the office?
我不是叫妳去打掃書房嗎？
Right away, ma'am!
我立刻就去！
Go easy on the gardening, alright?
玩園藝要適可而止，好嗎？
She's a tough opponent.
她還真難對付
-What does this mean? -I don't know…
-這是什麼意思？ -我也不曉得…
Excuse me, sir.
打擾了
You know about the new Pure Concubine in the Garnet Pavilion, yes?
新的淑妃已經進了柘榴宮 這件事妳知道吧？
Yes…
知道
The successor for Concubine Ah-Duo, who left?
是阿多妃的繼任者？
The rear palace wants to educate this new concubine.
後宮想要幫這位新來的嬪妃講學
They want you to be the instructor.
說是要讓妳去當講師
You must be joking.
您在說笑吧？
Why would I make such a joke?
誰跟妳說笑？
Here's the name of the person who recommended you.
這上面還寫著推薦人的名字呢
Recommended me?
推薦人？
And there's another one.
還有另一人
Lady Lihua…
連梨花娘娘都…
It must be that…
原來是那個啊…
So, I'm counting on you.
就是這樣，交給妳了
I can't ignore the request of two concubines…
兩位妃子都提出請求了 實在不能視若無睹
They even listed how much I would get paid.
甚至還仔細地寫上了賞賜的金額
Grams really ripped them off, huh?
是說老鴇還真是敲詐了一筆啊
Now's the chance…
趁現在…
Are these teaching supplies you'll use for your lessons?
這堆貨物是講學的教材嗎？
Yes. And here's the bill.
對，這是帳單
Just this?
就這樣嗎？
The color of the ink is different here.
好像只有這裡的墨水顏色不一樣呢
She's really tough!
還真是難纏
With her around, I can't be ripping off Young Master.
只要這位婆婆在少爺身邊 恐怕很難敲詐他吧
What's inside?
裡面有什麼？
I can't have him seeing my precious teaching supplies!
我可不能讓您看到珍貴的教材
Hiss!
走開！
Fine, I won't look.
知道了，不看就是了
Should I help you carry these?
需要幫忙嗎？
No thank you.
不用麻煩
If I have to do this, I'll go all in!
要做就要做得徹底
It's been a while being in this environment.
這個感覺還真是久違了
The feminine atmosphere calms me.
都是女性的氛圍讓人莫名放鬆呢
-It's Sir Jinshi! -He's as beautiful as always.
-是壬氏大人！ -今天也是如此俊美
There are a lot of spectators today.
聚集了不少人呢
They probably heard rumors about the lessons.
可能是聽到了講學的事情，來圍觀吧
Listen up.
我先說清楚
The classes are only open to high-ranking concubines.
要接受講學的只有上級妃子
If that's not you, step back.
無關的人就退下吧
Is this eunuch some kind of supernatural figure?
這位宦官是什麼妖怪嗎？
You mustn't!
您不能進來！
Why?
為何？
You said yourself that the lessons are for high-ranking concubines only.
能接受講學的只有上級妃子 這是壬氏大人您自己說的
But…
但是…
He's stronger than he looks!
他比看起來的還要結實
Beyond this point is a top-confidential secret art only for women!
接下來要講的是 只限女性使用，不可外傳的秘術
Lady Gyokuyou is as beautiful as ever.
玉葉娘娘還是一樣美麗
Looks like Ms. Hongniang is doing well, too.
紅娘大人似乎也沒什麼改變
Lady Lishu seems to be nervous.
里樹娘娘似乎有點畏縮
Well, it can't be helped, with three other high-ranking concubines here.
和其他三位上級妃子共處一室 這也是情有可原
As long as the food taster attendant is there, she should be alright.
只要試毒人侍女陪在身邊 狀況應該會比以前好吧
Lady Lihua, too.
梨花娘娘也是
Her rich figure has returned, and she seems to be doing well.
她幾乎恢復了原本豐滿的體態 氣色也很不錯
That attendant is from the face powder incident…
那位侍女是白粉意外那時候的…
She doesn't need to be that scared!
不用警戒成這樣吧？
Finally, the successor to Concubine Ah-Duo.
最後，繼阿多妃之後上位的妃子
The new Pure Concubine, Concubine Loulan.
新來的淑妃，樓蘭妃
Does she prefer those southern-style flashy clothes?
她喜好南國風格的華麗服飾嗎？
Her facial features seem more northern,
容貌特徵看起來雖然像是北方出身
but I can't really tell…
但我實在不確定
Based on her age, the Emperor will probably visit her at night.
依年齡來看，皇帝應該會臨幸她吧
Looks like the rear palace's balance will be maintained for now, but…
看起來不像是 會擾亂後宮平衡的人，但是…
Whatever. That's not my business.
算了，不關我的事
I'll be your instructor for today.
我是負責這次講學的講師
My name is Maomao.
我叫貓貓
What I'll be teaching you today
現在開始要教授給大家的
is a secret art to be used in the garden of women.
是女性專用的秘術
Please keep it confidential.
請勿流傳出去
Now, I'll hand out the teaching supplies.
那麼，我現在就將教材發下去
What do you think is going on?
裡面究竟發生了什麼事呢？
I can't tell…
我也不曉得…
All done… Huh?
終於結束了，咦？
Good work. You took a while.
辛苦了，花了很多時間呢
He must've been eavesdropping.
這傢伙是在偷聽吧？
What's going on?
怎麼了？
What happened here?
這到底是什麼狀況？
You gotta change things up, you know?
換個玩法
Touch this like this…
像這樣觸碰…
I can't. I can't do it.
做不到，絕對做不到！
Lady Lishu!
里樹娘娘！
I just gave my lesson, like you asked.
我只是照您吩咐的那樣講課而已
Looks like the two recommenders were satisfied with my lesson.
而且兩位推薦人看起來很滿意
I couldn't tell what she was thinking to the very end.
直到最後都看不出在她想什麼呢
Use that any way you'd like.
隨她高興去吧
What kind of lesson was it?
方才是講授了什麼內容？
You can ask the Emperor for his opinion later.
請日後再向皇帝詢問感想吧
Hey!
喂！
I'm so tired…
好累啊
I'm so excited to get paid!
賞金真是令人期待
This way!
這邊！
I'd better not. So cold!
還是算了吧，好冷！
Sir Lakan? Sir Lakan!
羅漢大人？
Sir Lakan, I looked all over for you!
羅漢大人，我到處在找您
Does something bother you?
有什麼讓您在意的嗎？
No. It's nothing.
沒有，沒事
What was the commotion last night?
昨晚的騷動是怎麼回事？
He's a eunuch, but he also has work
明明是個宦官，卻不只負責後宮
for the outer palace, too?
也得處理外廷的事務嗎？
Seems like he can't ignore proposed laws, no matter how silly they are.
不管是多無趣的法案 他似乎都無法忽視
It's good paper. Selling it would make some money.
這是上等的紙 賣掉的話能夠小賺一筆
What a waste to burn these.
得燒掉還真可惜
The garbage incinerator is near the military base…
垃圾焚化場在軍府附近…
Xiaomao.
小貓
It's cold outside.
外頭很冷
Thank you, sir.
非常謝謝您
He's watchful, as always. What a waste that he's just a eunuch.
真是貼心，當個宦官實在太可惜了
This is from Sir Jinshi!
這是壬氏大人要給妳的
I merely handed it to you!
我只是負責交給妳而已
I see.
是喔
He even needs permission to hand over one padded gown to a maid?
就連拿一件棉襖給婢女 也得獲得批准才行嗎？
Must be tough.
真是辛苦了
Thank you, Sir Jinshi.
謝謝您，壬氏大人
Don't worry about it.
別放在心上
The outer palace is several times bigger than the rear palace,
外廷比後宮大上好幾倍
but I can't find many medicinal herbs.
但我沒發現太多藥草
Looks like the only usable herbs are dandelions and mugworts,
看來能用的藥草，只有隨處可見的
which I can find anywhere…
蒲公英和艾草了吧
It's winter, so plants are hard to find, but still…
冬天本來就不好找植物
I should plant some seeds around here.
還是該在這附近灑下一些種子呢？
Red spider lily!
是石蒜！
Here, and here!
這裡有，那裡也有！
The bulbs taste so good when you soak them in water!
把球根泡在水中之後會非常美味
If you mess up removing the poison,
雖然沒有把毒素處理乾淨的話
you'll suffer from a stomach ache, but…
會引發腸胃不適，但是…
Sir Lihaku? His ribbon is a different color than before…
李白大人？ 他腰帶的顏色與之前不同…
Did he get promoted?
也就是說，他又升官了？
Oh, hey, miss!
喔，小姑娘
Sir Lihaku.
李白大人
Are you here with a concubine?
妳是陪著妃子來的嗎？
It must be unusual, leaving the rear palace.
看到妳離開後宮還真難得
He doesn't know I was fired?
他不知道我被解僱的事情嗎？
This is Sir Lihaku. He's in love with Big Sis Pairin, one of the
這位是李白大人，他愛上了白鈴姐姐
Three Princesses of the Verdigris House.
綠青館三姬的其中一位
He's a loveable idiot,
他是個為了女人努力升官
trying to get promoted for a woman.
有討喜也有傻氣之處的男子
To call for Big Sis Pairin,
若想指名白鈴姐姐的話
you need about half a year worth of salary for the common man.
一般百姓得花上半年所賺的銀子
She's too expensive to call upon frequently.
太過昂貴了，所以無法常常指名
I hear he comes to the Verdigris House often to have tea with apprentice girls.
聽說他經常到綠青館 找見習娼妓小丫頭喝茶
But he never ran into her.
但他從沒巧遇過就是了
Now that he tasted the heavenly syrup,
嚐過天上甘蜜滋味的男人
he visits frequently to get at least one look at her.
為求見一面而經常造訪
He's a hard worker, huh?
他也真是夠努力的了
-Huh? What's wrong? -Nothing.
-怎麼了嗎？ -沒事
I don't work in the rear palace anymore.
我現在已經從後宮的職位
I work as an assigned live-in servant for someone.
變成了某位大人的貼身侍女了
An assigned servant? That person has some strange taste!
貼身侍女？ 是哪位大人品味這麼特殊？
I agree with you.
對啊，品味很特殊呢
You must be on some business.
話說回來，大人似乎在忙些什麼？
Yeah, that's right.
是啊
It's a small fire. Not rare at this time of year.
發生了場小火災，這個季節很常見
They don't know the source, so I'm here to investigate.
他們找不到起火點 所以我來這裡調查
A mysterious fire, huh?
原因不明嗎？
The commotion last night must be from this.
昨天的騷動就是因為這個吧
Anyone injured?
有人受傷嗎？
Just the warehouse guard. His life isn't in danger…
只有倉庫的看守人 性命沒有大礙就是了
Hey, don't get too close.
喂，別靠得太近
Got it!
我知道
He tells me all that,
聽了這些事之後
and then he tells me not to get involved?
才叫我不要插手？
The coal reached all the way to the next room.
煤灰染到了隔壁的小屋
The debris scattered all around the building.
碎塊散落在建築物四周
This isn't a fire. It's an explosion.
與其說是小火災，更像是爆炸
I see.
原來如此
So they suspect it might be arson, huh?
他們是在懷疑有人縱火吧？
Now I know why Sir Lihaku, and not just some
我現在明白為何是找李白大人
lowly official, is here to investigate.
而不是位階較低的官吏了
If it's just some warehouse, they may not care.
若是尋常的倉庫也就算了
But this happened in the Emperor's Court.
但這場意外可是發生在宮廷內
This country is relatively peaceful,
這個國家大體上算是國泰民安
but not everyone is satisfied with the current state of things.
但不是每個人都滿足於現狀
Foreign troops sometimes attack us,
邊疆民族偶爾會來犯
and there have been some famines and droughts.
也不是完全沒有饑荒或旱災
We don't know for how long peace with other nations will continue.
與外國的和平關係不知道能維持多久
There must be foreign countries dissatisfied with the status quo.
異國之中想必也有人心懷不滿
Is this charcoal? No, it's a burnt potato. How wasteful.
是木炭？不是 是燒焦的薯類，真是糟蹋啊
This must be a food storage space, then.
所以說，這裡應該是糧倉
Is this ivory work? Looks like a pipe.
這是象牙雕飾嗎？似乎是根菸管
Don't just wander around!
快別到處亂晃了！
A smoking pipe…
菸管…
Explosion, food storage warehouse,
爆炸、糧倉
Oh…
喔
Hey!
喂！
Are you listening?
妳有在聽嗎？
I can hear you.
我有聽到
But not listening.
只是沒聽進去
Was the burned warehouse arranged like this room?
失火的倉庫跟這間倉庫裡 放的東西一樣嗎？
Yeah. Looks like the old stuff goes in the back.
對，越往裡頭堆的東西越舊的樣子
Can I have this?
這個可以給我嗎？
That's probably fine.
應該可以吧
Also this. And I'd need a hammer, a saw,
還有這個，我還需要木槌和鋸子
and some nails.
和一些釘子
What are you planning on doing?
妳打算做什麼？
Just a little experiment.
做個小實驗
All set.
這樣就完成了
You're weirdly good at this.
這種事妳倒是很熟練
I grew up a peasant. I'm good at making things we don't have.
因為出身貧寒 所以我挺擅長自己做需要的東西
That's flour, right?
那是麵粉，對吧？
Yes. It was in the storage.
對，從倉庫裡拿出來的
Is this good?
這樣就可以了嗎？
And the kindling coal I asked for?
還有拜託您準備的火種呢？
-It's right here. -Thank you, sir.
-在這裡 -謝謝您
What the heck is going on?
完全看不懂
We're all ready to go. It's dangerous, so please step back.
準備完成了，這很危險還請退後
Oh, alright.
好的
Be careful, Sir Lihaku.
李白大人，很危險喔
What's so dangerous?
有什麼好危險的？
No matter what you do, miss, I'm a soldier. I'll be fine.
不就是小姑娘做點什麼 我一個堂堂武官哪會有危險？
Fine. Do what you'd like.
我明白了
It's dangerous, so be careful.
這很危險，請大人務必要小心
Run away quickly, alright?
要立刻躲遠喔
What? What do you mean, run?
什麼？是要躲什麼啊？
Erase it right now!
快來滅火！
Didn't I tell you?
所以我不就說了嗎？
So, what did what to cause an explosion?
那麼，爆炸的原因是什麼？
This is the cause.
原因在此
Flour?
麵粉？
Yes. Powder like flour and buckwheat is highly flammable,
對，麵粉或蕎麥粉很容易燃燒
and when it scatters in the air, it can catch fire.
粉末飄散在空中時，有時會著火
And this started the fire.
起火原因是這個
A smoking pipe?
菸管？
If you sneak inside for a smoke,
如果偷溜進倉庫抽菸
the outside air flows inside, causing the flour to scatter.
外頭的空氣流入室內後 就會揚起粉末
If you light the smoking pipe in that environment…
這時再點起菸管的話…
The flour that filled the entire warehouse will ignite,
滿佈整間倉庫的麵粉便會著火
causing an explosion.
結果就引發了爆炸
You should tell the guards not to smoke inside the warehouse.
能請您轉告倉庫看守人 不要在倉庫抽菸嗎？
How did you even know that?
妳怎麼連這種事都知道？
I've accidentally blown up a room I was renting in the Verdigris House.
以前我曾經把 跟綠青館租借的房間炸掉了
You…
妳…
You stupid girl!
妳這個愚蠢的姑娘！
Grams was so scary then…
那時的婆婆實在可怕啊
But it's strange to think
但是粉末竟然能夠引起爆炸
that powder can explode.
真是不可思議啊
There are very few strange things in this world.
這世上不可思議的事並不多
If you think it's strange, it just means you didn't know.
會覺得不可思議 就只是還不明白而已
Be careful not to catch a cold.
小心別著涼了
If you do, Luomen's medicines in the pleasure district will work well.
真的著涼的話 煙花巷有個羅門的藥很有效喔
Old Man is bad at selling.
老爹很不會做生意
I have to contribute sometimes.
多少得幫忙一下
He can stop by when he visits Big Sis Pairin.
當他去看白鈴姐姐的時候 可以順道過去一下
-I'll be going back to work, then. -Okay.
-那我回去工作了 -好
I brought this by accident.
不小心把這個帶回來了
If I clean this up and add a new mouthpiece, would it work?
擦拭乾淨後再裝上新的吸嘴 應該就能恢復原狀了吧？
It could sell for a good amount of money.
這應該可以賣個好價錢吧
This is too nice for a warehouse guard to own.
不過，以倉庫看守人來說 這根菸管也太奢侈了吧
Maybe it's something precious.
該不會是很寶貝的東西吧？
I should polish this and return it to him.
處理好再還回去吧
Shit!
可惡！
I can do it too… Shit…
這我也辦得到，可惡…
PREVIEW OF NEXT EPISODE
（下集預告）
Next episode, "Raw Fish."
下一集，《魚膾》
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻譯：歐德慧